<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<document-metadata version="1.0" xmlns="http://breeze.macromedia.com/">
	<document-info>
		<title>Maths Skills</title>
		<summary></summary>
		<author/>
		<keywords/>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000001.jpg"/>
		<view-link href="/index.htm?slide={{position}}" href-html5="/index.htm?slide={{position}}" href-swf="/"/>
	</document-info>
	<section type="slide" position="1" xmlns="">
		<title>Kinetic Energy Practice</title>
		<content>Kinetic Energy&amp;#x0A;Practice It’s your turn to put these skills into practice. Just like the previous practice, questions will get progressively harder, but no matter how small or big the number, the technique is still the same. The equation will be on every page to help you. Complete the questions and fill in the correct answer – you need 4/5 to progress. A calculator is below and remember to answer to 2 decimal places! Kinetic Energy&amp;#x0A;Practice It’s your turn to put these skills into practice. Just like the previous practice, questions will get progressively harder, but no matter how small or big the number, the technique is still the same. The equation will be on every page to help you. Complete the questions and fill in the correct answer – you need 4/5 to progress. A calculator is below and remember to answer to 2 decimal places! </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000001.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="2" xmlns="">
		<title>A man throws a tennis ball for his dog. At it’s highest point, the ball is 4 metres from the ground. The mass of a tennis ball is 58.5 grams (0.0585 kg). Using 9.81 for g, calculate the tennis ball’s gravitational potential energy to 1 decimal place.</title>
		<content> A man throws a tennis ball for his dog. At it’s highest point, the ball is 4 metres from the ground. The mass of a tennis ball is 58.5 grams (0.0585 kg). Using 9.81 for g, calculate the tennis ball’s gravitational potential energy to 1 decimal place.  Correct - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue Incorrect - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue You answered this correctly! Your answer: The correct answer is: You did not answer this question completely You must answer the question before continuing Submit Clear  A man throws a tennis ball for his dog. At it’s highest point, the ball is 4 metres from the ground. The mass of a tennis ball is 58.5 grams (0.0585 kg). Using 9.81 for g, calculate the tennis ball’s gravitational potential energy to 1 decimal place.  Correct - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue Incorrect - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue You answered this correctly! Your answer: The correct answer is: You did not answer this question completely You must answer the question before continuing Submit Clear </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000002.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="3" xmlns="">
		<title>An Orca whale can jump as high as 4.5 metres out of the water and can weight as much as 5,400 kg. Using 9.81 for g, calculate its gravitational potential energy.</title>
		<content> An Orca whale can jump as high as 4.5 metres out of the water and can weight as much as 5,400 kg. Using 9.81 for g, calculate its gravitational potential energy.  Correct - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue Incorrect - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue You answered this correctly! Your answer: The correct answer is: You did not answer this question completely You must answer the question before continuing Submit Clear  An Orca whale can jump as high as 4.5 metres out of the water and can weight as much as 5,400 kg. Using 9.81 for g, calculate its gravitational potential energy.  Correct - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue Incorrect - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue You answered this correctly! Your answer: The correct answer is: You did not answer this question completely You must answer the question before continuing Submit Clear </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000003.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="4" xmlns="">
		<title>In 2005, a Guinness world record attempt let loose a peregrine falcon at a height of 3 miles (4,828 metres) to see how fast it could fly. “Frightful” only weighed 997.9 grams (0.9979 kg). What was her gravitational potential energy to 2 decimal places?</title>
		<content> In 2005, a Guinness world record attempt let loose a peregrine falcon at a height of 3 miles (4,828 metres) to see how fast it could fly. “Frightful” only weighed 997.9 grams (0.9979 kg). What was her gravitational potential energy to 2 decimal places?  Correct - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue Incorrect - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue You answered this correctly! Your answer: The correct answer is: You did not answer this question completely You must answer the question before continuing Submit Clear  In 2005, a Guinness world record attempt let loose a peregrine falcon at a height of 3 miles (4,828 metres) to see how fast it could fly. “Frightful” only weighed 997.9 grams (0.9979 kg). What was her gravitational potential energy to 2 decimal places?  Correct - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue Incorrect - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue You answered this correctly! Your answer: The correct answer is: You did not answer this question completely You must answer the question before continuing Submit Clear </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000004.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="5" xmlns="">
		<title>The average sky diver jumps out of a plane at 4,000 metres. Use 85 kg for the mans mass and 9.81 for g. Calculate the sky divers G.P.E.</title>
		<content>The average sky diver jumps out of a plane at 4,000 metres. Use 85 kg for the mans mass and 9.81 for g. Calculate the sky divers G.P.E.  Correct - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue Incorrect - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue You answered this correctly! Your answer: The correct answer is: You did not answer this question completely You must answer the question before continuing Submit Clear  The average sky diver jumps out of a plane at 4,000 metres. Use 85 kg for the mans mass and 9.81 for g. Calculate the sky divers G.P.E.  Correct - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue Incorrect - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue You answered this correctly! Your answer: The correct answer is: You did not answer this question completely You must answer the question before continuing Submit Clear  </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000005.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="6" xmlns="">
		<title>Jupiter is nearly 11 times bigger than Earth. It’s gravitational field strength is 24.79 N/kg. Calculate a sky diver’s G.P.E whilst falling from a plane at 4,000 metres above Saturn. Keep 85 kg for the mass.</title>
		<content> Jupiter is nearly 11 times bigger than Earth. It’s gravitational field strength is 24.79 N/kg. Calculate a sky diver’s G.P.E whilst falling from a plane at 4,000 metres above Saturn. Keep 85 kg for the mass.  Correct - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue Incorrect - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue You answered this correctly! Your answer: The correct answer is: You did not answer this question completely You must answer the question before continuing Submit Clear   Jupiter is nearly 11 times bigger than Earth. It’s gravitational field strength is 24.79 N/kg. Calculate a sky diver’s G.P.E whilst falling from a plane at 4,000 metres above Saturn. Keep 85 kg for the mass.  Correct - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue Incorrect - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue You answered this correctly! Your answer: The correct answer is: You did not answer this question completely You must answer the question before continuing Submit Clear  </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000006.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="7" xmlns="">
		<title>Graphical Potential Energy Quiz</title>
		<content>Graphical Potential Energy Quiz Your ScoreMax ScoreNumber of Quiz Attempts Question Feedback/Review Information Will Appear Here Review Quiz Continue Graphical Potential Energy Quiz Your ScoreMax ScoreNumber of Quiz Attempts Question Feedback/Review Information Will Appear Here Review Quiz Continue </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000007.jpg"/>
	</section>
</document-metadata>
