<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<document-metadata version="1.0" xmlns="http://breeze.macromedia.com/">
	<document-info>
		<title>Maths Skills</title>
		<summary></summary>
		<author/>
		<keywords/>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000001.jpg"/>
		<view-link href="/index.htm?slide={{position}}" href-html5="/index.htm?slide={{position}}" href-swf="/"/>
	</document-info>
	<section type="slide" position="1" xmlns="">
		<title>Maths Skills</title>
		<content>Maths Skills This quick guide is going to walk you through some simple techniques to make the dreaded word ‘maths’ easier to use. Physics often needs mathematics to be applied to it in order for it to make sense. Maths Skills This quick guide is going to walk you through some simple techniques to make the dreaded word ‘maths’ easier to use. Physics often needs mathematics to be applied to it in order for it to make sense. </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000001.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="2" xmlns="">
		<title>Objectives</title>
		<content>Objectives By the end of this short course, you should be able to; Apply basic mathematics skills to a problem confidently; Understand how to tackle algebra confidently; Apply mathematical skills to a concept in physics, including the use of standard units. Objectives By the end of this short course, you should be able to; Apply basic mathematics skills to a problem confidently; Understand how to tackle algebra confidently; Apply mathematical skills to a concept in physics, including the use of standard units. </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000002.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="3" xmlns="">
		<title>Before we begin…</title>
		<content>Before we begin… Mathematics is a love/hate topic. It’s understandable from all the rote learning and constant practice at school. We won’t be doing any of that! Whilst there are assessments in throughout this web application, they aren’t designed to elicit any negative emotions… Assessments are designed to make you think, and instil a sense of confidence when tackling problems. Before we begin… Mathematics is a love/hate topic. It’s understandable from all the rote learning and constant practice at school. We won’t be doing any of that! Whilst there are assessments in throughout this web application, they aren’t designed to elicit any negative emotions… Assessments are designed to make you think, and instil a sense of confidence when tackling problems. </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000003.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="4" xmlns="">
		<title>1. Maths using shapes</title>
		<content>1. Maths using shapes We all know the following equation; But a primary school student is taught this equation in a slightly different way…       = +        This means that both sides of the equation must equal the same value. This single piece of information that helps unlock algebra is often the first piece of information that is forgotten. I will keep referring to the balance of the equation throughout the lessons. 1. Maths using shapes We all know the following equation; But a primary school student is taught this equation in a slightly different way…       = +        This means that both sides of the equation must equal the same value. This single piece of information that helps unlock algebra is often the first piece of information that is forgotten. I will keep referring to the balance of the equation throughout the lessons. </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000004.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="5" xmlns="">
		<title>Problem #1</title>
		<content>Problem #1 I want you to recreate the same problem as before using the shapes below. You can use more than one shape.        Problem #1 I want you to recreate the same problem as before using the shapes below. You can use more than one shape.        </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000005.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="6" xmlns="">
		<title>Problem #1</title>
		<content>Problem #1 I want you to recreate the same problem as before using the shapes below. You can use more than one shape.       1 2 3 4  2  2  4 = + Problem #1 I want you to recreate the same problem as before using the shapes below. You can use more than one shape.       1 2 3 4  2  2  4 = + </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000006.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="7" xmlns="">
		<title>Problem #2</title>
		<content>Problem #2 Knowing the value for each shape is crucial to solving a mathematical problem.       1 2 3 4 = -  4  1  3 Problem #2 Knowing the value for each shape is crucial to solving a mathematical problem.       1 2 3 4 = -  4  1  3 </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000007.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="8" xmlns="">
		<title>Complete the sum</title>
		<content>Complete the sum Correct - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue Incorrect - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue You answered this correctly! Your answer: The correct answer is: You did not answer this question completely You must answer the question before continuing Submit Clear   = x 1.     1 2 3 4 ? A) 2 B) 4 C) 6 D) 8 E) 12 Complete the sum Correct - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue Incorrect - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue You answered this correctly! Your answer: The correct answer is: You did not answer this question completely You must answer the question before continuing Submit Clear   = x 1.     1 2 3 4 ? A) 2 B) 4 C) 6 D) 8 E) 12 </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000008.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="9" xmlns="">
		<title>Complete the sum</title>
		<content>Complete the sum Correct - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue Incorrect - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue You answered this correctly! Your answer: The correct answer is: You did not answer this question completely You must answer the question before continuing Submit Clear   = ? x 2.     1 2 3 4 A) 4 B) 6 C) 8 D) 10 E) 12 Complete the sum Correct - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue Incorrect - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue You answered this correctly! Your answer: The correct answer is: You did not answer this question completely You must answer the question before continuing Submit Clear   = ? x 2.     1 2 3 4 A) 4 B) 6 C) 8 D) 10 E) 12 </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000009.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="10" xmlns="">
		<title>Complete the sum</title>
		<content>Complete the sum Correct - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue Incorrect - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue You answered this correctly! Your answer: The correct answer is: You did not answer this question completely You must answer the question before continuing Submit Clear     1 2 3 4    = ? x + ( ) 3. A) 2 B) 3 C) 4 D) 5 E) 6 Complete the sum Correct - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue Incorrect - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue You answered this correctly! Your answer: The correct answer is: You did not answer this question completely You must answer the question before continuing Submit Clear     1 2 3 4    = ? x + ( ) 3. A) 2 B) 3 C) 4 D) 5 E) 6 </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000010.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="11" xmlns="">
		<title>Quiz</title>
		<content>Quiz Your ScoreMax ScoreNumber of Quiz Attempts Question Feedback/Review Information Will Appear Here Review Quiz Continue Quiz Your ScoreMax ScoreNumber of Quiz Attempts Question Feedback/Review Information Will Appear Here Review Quiz Continue </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000011.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="12" xmlns="">
		<title>Conclusions</title>
		<content>Conclusions Trying to solve an equation with shapes that have no value is impossible; Once you know the values of each shape, solving the mathematical equations become a lot easier; Think of shapes as ‘placeholders’ for numbers – you know the shape is a number, and you can find the value if you look for it in the right places; In this short example, I gave you the numbers and they are normally in the question somewhere. Conclusions Trying to solve an equation with shapes that have no value is impossible; Once you know the values of each shape, solving the mathematical equations become a lot easier; Think of shapes as ‘placeholders’ for numbers – you know the shape is a number, and you can find the value if you look for it in the right places; In this short example, I gave you the numbers and they are normally in the question somewhere. </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000012.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="13" xmlns="">
		<title>2. Maths using words</title>
		<content>2. Maths using words This is the same principle as maths using shapes, however some Roald Dahl-esque words will now have a mathematical value. This means you will need to apply the same concepts as before but instead of shapes, replace the word with a number. 2. Maths using words This is the same principle as maths using shapes, however some Roald Dahl-esque words will now have a mathematical value. This means you will need to apply the same concepts as before but instead of shapes, replace the word with a number. </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000013.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="14" xmlns="">
		<title>2. Maths using words</title>
		<content>2. Maths using words Swatchscoppler = 5  Flooplesplink = 10 Dugenheimer = 20 Zoobeddy = 25 2. Maths using words Swatchscoppler = 5  Flooplesplink = 10 Dugenheimer = 20 Zoobeddy = 25 </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000014.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="15" xmlns="">
		<title>Problem #3</title>
		<content>Problem #3 On one side of the equation lies two Dugenheimer’s and on the other side is a Zoobeddy and a swatchscoppler. What other word is missing to balance out the equation? Swatchscoppler = 5  Flooplesplink = 10 Dugenheimer = 20 Zoobeddy = 25 = Dugenheimer Dugenheimer Zoobeddy Swatchscoppler  Flooplesplink = 10 Swatchscoppler = 5  Zoobeddy = 25 Dugenheimer = 20 Dugenheimer = 20 Problem #3 On one side of the equation lies two Dugenheimer’s and on the other side is a Zoobeddy and a swatchscoppler. What other word is missing to balance out the equation? Swatchscoppler = 5  Flooplesplink = 10 Dugenheimer = 20 Zoobeddy = 25 = Dugenheimer Dugenheimer Zoobeddy Swatchscoppler  Flooplesplink = 10 Swatchscoppler = 5  Zoobeddy = 25 Dugenheimer = 20 Dugenheimer = 20 </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000015.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="16" xmlns="">
		<title>Problem #4</title>
		<content>Problem #4 We can do something more complex too! What is missing to balance out the equation? Swatchscoppler = 5  Flooplesplink = 10 Dugenheimer = 20 Zoobeddy = 25 = 10 Flooplesplink’s How many Zoobeddy’s? 5 Zoobeddy’s = Flooplesplink x Flooplesplink Swatchscoppler x  Zoobeddy Problem #4 We can do something more complex too! What is missing to balance out the equation? Swatchscoppler = 5  Flooplesplink = 10 Dugenheimer = 20 Zoobeddy = 25 = 10 Flooplesplink’s How many Zoobeddy’s? 5 Zoobeddy’s = Flooplesplink x Flooplesplink Swatchscoppler x  Zoobeddy </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000016.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="17" xmlns="">
		<title>250 = ???</title>
		<content>250 = ??? Correct - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue Incorrect - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue You answered this correctly! Your answer: The correct answer is: You did not answer this question completely You must answer the question before continuing Submit Clear Swatchscoppler = 5 Flooplesplink = 10Dugenheimer = 20Zoobeddy = 25 A) Swatchscoppler x Zoobeddy B) Zoobeddy x Zoobeddy C) Floopsplink x Dugenheimer D) Flooplesplink x Zoobeddy 250 = ??? Correct - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue Incorrect - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue You answered this correctly! Your answer: The correct answer is: You did not answer this question completely You must answer the question before continuing Submit Clear Swatchscoppler = 5 Flooplesplink = 10Dugenheimer = 20Zoobeddy = 25 A) Swatchscoppler x Zoobeddy B) Zoobeddy x Zoobeddy C) Floopsplink x Dugenheimer D) Flooplesplink x Zoobeddy </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000017.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="18" xmlns="">
		<title>Zoobeddy ÷ Swatschoppler = ???</title>
		<content>Zoobeddy ÷ Swatschoppler = ??? Correct - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue Incorrect - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue You answered this correctly! Your answer: The correct answer is: You did not answer this question completely You must answer the question before continuing Submit Clear Swatchscoppler = 5 Flooplesplink = 10Dugenheimer = 20Zoobeddy = 25 A) Swatchscoppler B) 10 C) Flooplesplink D) 5 Zoobeddy ÷ Swatschoppler = ??? Correct - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue Incorrect - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue You answered this correctly! Your answer: The correct answer is: You did not answer this question completely You must answer the question before continuing Submit Clear Swatchscoppler = 5 Flooplesplink = 10Dugenheimer = 20Zoobeddy = 25 A) Swatchscoppler B) 10 C) Flooplesplink D) 5 </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000018.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="19" xmlns="">
		<title>If we have three Dugenheimer's, two Zoobeddy's and nine Flooplesplink's and three, what is the total value?</title>
		<content>If we have three Dugenheimer's, two Zoobeddy's and nine Flooplesplink's and three, what is the total value? Correct - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue Incorrect - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue You answered this correctly! Your answer: The correct answer is: You did not answer this question completely You must answer the question before continuing Submit Clear Swatchscoppler = 5 Flooplesplink = 10Dugenheimer = 20Zoobeddy = 25 A) 193 B) 215 C) 203 D) 243 If we have three Dugenheimer's, two Zoobeddy's and nine Flooplesplink's and three, what is the total value? Correct - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue Incorrect - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue You answered this correctly! Your answer: The correct answer is: You did not answer this question completely You must answer the question before continuing Submit Clear Swatchscoppler = 5 Flooplesplink = 10Dugenheimer = 20Zoobeddy = 25 A) 193 B) 215 C) 203 D) 243 </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000019.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="20" xmlns="">
		<title>Words</title>
		<content>Words Your ScoreMax ScoreNumber of Quiz Attempts Question Feedback/Review Information Will Appear Here Review Quiz Continue Words Your ScoreMax ScoreNumber of Quiz Attempts Question Feedback/Review Information Will Appear Here Review Quiz Continue </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000020.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="21" xmlns="">
		<title>3. Algebra – Speed</title>
		<content>3. Algebra – Speed We are now going to look at an instance in physics of an equation that is commonly used in everyday life. “Galileo Galilei, an early Italian physicist was the first to measure speed defining it as a distance travelled per unit of time.” In the UK, we commonly use miles per hour, or distance per unit of time as a measure of speed. i.e. 70 miles per hour, is 70 miles travelled in one hour. 3. Algebra – Speed We are now going to look at an instance in physics of an equation that is commonly used in everyday life. “Galileo Galilei, an early Italian physicist was the first to measure speed defining it as a distance travelled per unit of time.” In the UK, we commonly use miles per hour, or distance per unit of time as a measure of speed. i.e. 70 miles per hour, is 70 miles travelled in one hour. </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000021.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="22" xmlns="">
		<title>Speed</title>
		<content>Speed Even though miles per hour is a common measure of speed, physicists like to have standardised units. - For distance, physicists often use metres (m). - And for time, physicists often use seconds (s). - Speed is therefore metres per second (m/s).           Speed Even though miles per hour is a common measure of speed, physicists like to have standardised units. - For distance, physicists often use metres (m). - And for time, physicists often use seconds (s). - Speed is therefore metres per second (m/s).           </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000022.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="23" xmlns="">
		<title>Speed – problem #5</title>
		<content>Speed – problem #5 A car travelled 130 miles in 2 hours. What was its speed in miles per hour?   Where; v = speed (mph) d = distance (miles) t = time (hours)             Speed – problem #5 A car travelled 130 miles in 2 hours. What was its speed in miles per hour?   Where; v = speed (mph) d = distance (miles) t = time (hours)             </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000023.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="24" xmlns="">
		<title>Speed – problem #6</title>
		<content>Speed – problem #6 A car travelled 130 miles at 65 mph. How long did it take to travel to its destination?   Where; v = speed (mph) d = distance (miles) t = time (hours)          d v t   ÷ ÷           Speed – problem #6 A car travelled 130 miles at 65 mph. How long did it take to travel to its destination?   Where; v = speed (mph) d = distance (miles) t = time (hours)          d v t   ÷ ÷           </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000024.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="25" xmlns="">
		<title>Speed – problem #7</title>
		<content>Speed – problem #7 A car travelled at 65 mph for 2 hours. What speed was it travelling? Where; v = speed (mph) d = distance (miles) t = time (hours)       d v t   ÷ ÷              Speed – problem #7 A car travelled at 65 mph for 2 hours. What speed was it travelling? Where; v = speed (mph) d = distance (miles) t = time (hours)       d v t   ÷ ÷              </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000025.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="26" xmlns="">
		<title>A cheetah chases its prey for a distance of 300 metres in 15 seconds. What is it's speed?</title>
		<content>A cheetah chases its prey for a distance of 300 metres in 15 seconds. What is it's speed? A) 20 m/s B) 22 m/s C) 15 m/s D) 18 m/s Correct - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue Incorrect - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue You answered this correctly! Your answer: The correct answer is: You did not answer this question completely You must answer the question before continuing Submit Clear A cheetah chases its prey for a distance of 300 metres in 15 seconds. What is it's speed? A) 20 m/s B) 22 m/s C) 15 m/s D) 18 m/s Correct - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue Incorrect - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue You answered this correctly! Your answer: The correct answer is: You did not answer this question completely You must answer the question before continuing Submit Clear </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000026.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="27" xmlns="">
		<title>A lorry is moving at 62mph for 8 hours. What is the distance travelled by the lorry?</title>
		<content>A lorry is moving at 62mph for 8 hours. What is the distance travelled by the lorry? A) 480 B) 496 C) 540 D) 558 Correct - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue Incorrect - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue You answered this correctly! Your answer: The correct answer is: You did not answer this question completely You must answer the question before continuing Submit Clear A lorry is moving at 62mph for 8 hours. What is the distance travelled by the lorry? A) 480 B) 496 C) 540 D) 558 Correct - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue Incorrect - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue You answered this correctly! Your answer: The correct answer is: You did not answer this question completely You must answer the question before continuing Submit Clear </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000027.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="28" xmlns="">
		<title>An asteroid travels at 2500 metres a second. How far does it travel in 1 hour (3600 seconds)?</title>
		<content>An asteroid travels at 2500 metres a second. How far does it travel in 1 hour (3600 seconds)? A) 2500 metres B) 150,000 metres C) 250,000 metres D) 900,000 metres E) 9,000,000 metres Correct - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue Incorrect - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue You answered this correctly! Your answer: The correct answer is: You did not answer this question completely You must answer the question before continuing Submit Clear An asteroid travels at 2500 metres a second. How far does it travel in 1 hour (3600 seconds)? A) 2500 metres B) 150,000 metres C) 250,000 metres D) 900,000 metres E) 9,000,000 metres Correct - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue Incorrect - Click anywhere or press Control Y to continue You answered this correctly! Your answer: The correct answer is: You did not answer this question completely You must answer the question before continuing Submit Clear </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000028.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="29" xmlns="">
		<title>Speed Equation</title>
		<content>Speed Equation Your ScoreMax ScoreNumber of Quiz Attempts Question Feedback/Review Information Will Appear Here Review Quiz Continue Speed Equation Your ScoreMax ScoreNumber of Quiz Attempts Question Feedback/Review Information Will Appear Here Review Quiz Continue </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000029.jpg"/>
	</section>
	<section type="slide" position="30" xmlns="">
		<title>Well done!</title>
		<content>Well done! You made it. I hope this has unlocked a few pieces of the puzzle that is mathematics and algebra. Hopefully you can now tick off some of the objectives below; Apply basic mathematics skills to a problem confidently; Understand how to tackle algebra confidently; Apply mathematical skills to a concept in physics, including the use of standard units. If not, don’t worry. There is more explanation on the maths further in the web application. Well done! You made it. I hope this has unlocked a few pieces of the puzzle that is mathematics and algebra. Hopefully you can now tick off some of the objectives below; Apply basic mathematics skills to a problem confidently; Understand how to tackle algebra confidently; Apply mathematical skills to a concept in physics, including the use of standard units. If not, don’t worry. There is more explanation on the maths further in the web application. </content>
		<related-content></related-content>
		<thumbnail href="data/thumb/thumb_slide_000030.jpg"/>
	</section>
</document-metadata>
